When creating documents within Word,
there may be occasions where you
wish to include some interactive
element within the document, such
as check boxes or dropdown lists.
To do this, you would need
to use the tools that are
featured on the developer tab.
So if you look at the top of your tool
bar, if the developer tab isn't available,
you would first need to activate it.
To do that, if you go along to the
Word menu and select preferences
and then ribbon and toolbar.
And on the ribbon and toolbar on
the right-hand side, you can see
that the main tabs are all ticked.
If the developer tab isn't ticked, you
would just need to tick that select save.
And then that will
activate the developer tab.
So once you're on the developer
tab, you'll see a range of tools
that can be used to add various
functionality to the document.
The two that we're going to focus
on are check boxes, and combo box.
So for this first letter, I'm just
going to add some simple check boxes.
What I need to do is place my cursor
to the right of the first option.
And I'm going to use a tab key to line
them up just a little bit further away.
And then I'm going to click the checkbox
icon, which will then insert a check box.
I will repeat that for
the next five options.
So move it down, tab key.
Add the checkbox, use the tab key
checkbox, again a tab key to line
them up and finally the last checkbox.
So now I have all the check boxes
inserted and they're all lined up
and now need to make them active.
And to do that, I need to
click on the protect form.
Once you've clicked on the protect
form button you can then select or
deselect the check boxes as required.
I can't edit any of the
rest of the document.
However anyone could unprotect
the form and then make changes.
To protect the document fully, you would
need to add a password and to do that
you would need to go to the tools menu.
From tools you would select
protect document that will then
allow you to add a password.
And the protection you're looking
for is to protect the document for
forms, add the password, select OK.
It will ask you to repeat
the password, select OK.
And that is now set.
So once the document has been
protected with a password by clicking
on that you would need to enter a
password to unprotect the document.
As well as adding check boxes,
there may be occasions where
you wish to add a dropdown box.
So as you can see, I've slightly
edited the letter that I was working
with and reduced some of the options.
I'm now going to add some dropdown
lists, which will indicate a specific
number and then the reader can then
select that number to say which
experience that they're interested in.
So again, I'm on the developer
tab and what I need to do, is
I'm going to add a combo box.
So I'm going to use the tab key
to space the dropdown list away
from the option, select a combo
box and then click on options.
Now it's basically asking me what I
want to include in the dropdown list.
So the first thing I'm
going to add some numbers.
So I click one and add that.
Two add that, three,
four, and finally five.
Add that.
So we now have all of the options
I want in the dropdown list, and
I'm just going to edit the name.
So it's just dropdown one, remove the
hyphen from there and click OK and that
will have added the drop-down list.
So if I click on that.,
nothing happens again.
You have to protect the form.
So once it's protected, I can then
make selections from the dropdown list.
I'll just unprotect the form again.
Now to repeat that for the next two
options, I would go again to the
combo box, do the options and add
the five numbers or whatever else
I wanted to add the dropdown box.
Alternatively, because I know that the
dropdown box is going to be the same
for both of the other experiences.
I can just highlight that and
use the Command and C to copy it
and go down to the next option.
Use Command and V and again for that
one Command and V and then if I protect
the form, I have now added the dropdown
lists to all three of the options.
As with the forms, if you wish to protect
it with a password, you would need to
go to the tools menu, and then select
protect document and add a password.